<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dandelbrot</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dandelbrot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A single factor CRD and the one-way analysis of variance</title>
      <link>/post/a-single-factor-crd-and-the-one-way-analysis-of-variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-single-factor-crd-and-the-one-way-analysis-of-variance/</guid>
      <description>I’m currently teaching a class on the statistical design of experiments, and we’re using SPSS currently. Shortly we’d like to switch to using R as the main statistical computing package. I also have a client who has asked me to teach her how to use R to perform basic one-way and two-way analysis of variance for data arising from completely randomised designs with single factor and 2-factorial treatment structure. This is child’s play, especially in R, but I thought I’d take the opportunity to work through a couple of good examples and record them here for future use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inverse Problems and Uncertainty Quantification</title>
      <link>/post/inverse-problems-and-uncertainty-quantification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/inverse-problems-and-uncertainty-quantification/</guid>
      <description>I’m interested in uncertainty quantification. There is a brief article in SIAM NEWS from 2014 which I just read that has piqued my interest further. The article, authored by Marco Iglesias and Andrew Stuart, discusses uncertainty quantification (UQ) in the context of inverse problems from a Bayesian perspective. Let’s have a look at the basic ideas set out in the article to get a feel for this important and “exciting area of research in the mathematical sciences” that brings together skills and knowledge from “analysis, computation, probability, and statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mandelbrot set in R</title>
      <link>/post/the-mandelbrot-set-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-mandelbrot-set-in-r/</guid>
      <description>This being my first post to Dandelbrot.com, I thought it only fitting to post something about the Mandelbrot set. I determined to code up a mandelbrot set fractal generator in R. After a little digging I came across this R-bloggers post from 2014. I figured, rather than reinvent the wheel, I might as well just borrow code from here, with all due kudos to Myles Harrison, the original author.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>